In this video, we're going to talk about programmer defined exceptions. So, think
在本视频中，我们将讨论程序员定义的异常。所以，我想
about the following typical programming scenario. You're deep into some fairly
关于以下典型的编程方案。你深陷一些公平的
complex section of code and you come to a place where you could experience an
复杂的代码段，您会来到一个地方，在那里您可以体验到
unexpected error. That there could be something that could happen that would
意外错误。可能会发生一些事情
violate some important property of your program. So, for example, maybe you're
违反程序的一些重要属性。所以，举个例子，也许你是
going to discover there's a place where you could be out of memory or there's some
你会发现有一个地方你可能没有记忆，或者有一些
data structure that doesn't satisfy some variant. So, a list that's supposed to be
不满足某些变体的数据结构。所以，一份应该是
sorted, that is not, or something like that. And the question is, how do you
分类的，那不是，或者类似的东西。问题是，你怎么
handle these errors? How do you write code that will handle the error gracefully and
是否处理这些错误？如何编写代码来优雅地处理错误，并
not make your program really, really ugly? So, a popular solution to this problem in
而不是让你的节目变得非常非常丑陋？因此，这个问题的一个流行解决方案是
many languages including Java is add a new kind of value to the language called an
包括Java在内的许多语言都给语言增加了一种新的价值，称为
exception. And we'll have a couple of control constructs for dealing with
例外情况。我们将有几个控件构造来处理
exceptions. Here is the two that are probably the most popular. And these are,
例外情况。这里有两个可能是最受欢迎的。这些是，
as they appear in Java. So, we can throw exceptions and what this does is it causes
因为它们出现在Java中。因此，我们可以抛出异常，这会导致
an exception to be created at this point wherever the throw occurs. And, that
此时无论发生抛出的位置都要创建异常。还有，那就是
exception will simply propagate out of the program. It will basically halt the
异常将简单地传播出程序。它将从根本上停止
execution of the program at that point and any containing constructs will also throw
在该点上执行程序和任何包含构造也将抛出
the exception. So, the exception will, you know, simply propagate up out of the code
例外情况。因此，您知道，异常将简单地向上传播到代码之外
that, that's currently executing, until it hits a try catch. So, how does this work?
那个，那个当前正在执行的，直到它命中了一个try catch。那么，这是怎么运作的呢？
Well, we can try something. We can execute some expression here and this will be some
嗯，我们可以试一试。我们可以在这里执行一些表达式，这将是一些
expression. And if this expression throws an exception, if the throw occurs
表达式。如果此表达式引发异常，如果发生抛出
somewhere inside this expression, then we will catch that exception and there can be
在此表达式中的某个位置，那么我们将捕获该异常，并且可以
a binding here to say what we are going to call the exception value. So, this is like
这里有一个绑定，用来表示我们将称之为异常值的内容。所以，这就像是
a let, we will grab the exception that comes out of here. We'll call it X and
首先，我们将捕获从这里传出的异常。我们就叫它X，然后
then we can execute this piece of cleanup code to how, to handle the exception in
然后，我们可以执行这段清理代码，以如何处理中的异常
some way. And so, the basic idea behind this thi design for handling exceptions,
以某种方式。因此，这个处理异常的设计背后的基本思想，
is that the place where you have the exception, the place where you actually
那是你有例外的地方吗，就是你实际
detect the exception, might be somewhere deep inside the code and not a very good
检测到异常，可能是在代码内部的某个位置，不是很好
place for actually dealing with the exception. So, what you want to do is get
实际处理异常的位置。所以，你要做的就是
out of that part of the code, get back to some higher level point where you can
在代码的这一部分之外，返回到某个更高级别的点，在那里您可以
clean things up deal with the exception, and then retry, perhaps, some larger block
进行清理，处理异常，然后重试，也许可以重试一些更大的挡路
of code. Here's a little example of using exceptions. So, here we have our main
代码。这里有一个使用异常的小示例。所以，这里我们有我们的主要
method. And what are we going to do? We're going to have a try-block that just calls
方法。那我们要做什么呢？我们要试一试--挡路只打个招呼
a function X. And if that raises a, an exception, then we will catch the
函数X。如果这引发了一个异常，那么我们将捕获
exception. In this case we don't do anything with the exception, we just print
例外情况。在本例中，我们对异常不做任何操作，我们只打印
out a message saying there was an error and we terminate the program. So, we don't
发出一条消息说出现错误，我们终止该程序。所以，我们不会
do anything very smart but we do catch the exception and at least print out an error
做任何非常聪明的事情，但是我们确实捕捉到了异常，并且至少打印出了一个错误
rather than just terminating. So, what does x do? Well, X simply throws an
而不是简单地终止。那么，x是做什么的呢？嗯，X只是抛出一个
exception. So this function X allocates an exception object. This is just a value,
例外情况。所以这个函数X分配一个异常对象。这只是一个值，
it's just a class like everything else. But it has a special property that it can
这只是一门课，就像其他所有的课一样。但它有一种特殊的性质，它可以
be thrown. So, when we throw it, that's when X terminates abnormally and we end up
被扔出去。所以，当我们抛出它的时候，就是X异常终止的时候，我们最终
in the catch block of the try-catch expression back in the main method. Now,
在Catch挡路的try-catch表达式中返回了Main方法。现在,
in the last couple of slides, I gave you a very informal description of how
在最后几张幻灯片中，我非常非正式地描述了
exceptions work and it, it might not have been very clear and in fact it's hard I
异常起作用，这可能不是很清楚，事实上我很难
think to give a very clear description without some kind of formal description of
认为在没有某种形式的描述的情况下给出一个非常清楚的描述
how exceptions are supposed to behave. But fortunately, we've looked at operational
异常应该如何表现。但幸运的是，我们已经看到了可操作的
semantics in this class and so now you're familiar with those kinds of descriptions
这个类中的语义，所以现在您已经熟悉了这些类型的描述
of language behavior and I can actually describe you pretty succinctly how
语言行为，我可以非常简洁地描述你是如何
try-catch actually really works, alright. So, we're going to give operational rules
Try-Catch真的很管用，好吧。所以，我们要给出操作规则
here for Try-Catch expressions. And I just noticed, I just poin t out here that I had
下面是try-catch表达式。我刚刚注意到，我只是在这里指出我有
some kind of font problem and so I had to write in the turnstiles by hand in this
一些字体问题，所以我不得不在旋转栅门上手写这个
slide. So those handwritten characters are all supposed to be the turnstile
滑行。所以那些手写的字符都应该是旋转门
character. Now, to more important things there's a distinction with exceptions.
性格。现在，对于更重要的事情，例外是有区别的。
Okay, there are two kinds of states that an exception object could be in. It could
好的，异常对象可能处于两种状态。它可能会
just be an ordinary value. So, when I say new exception object in Java, so, when I
只要做一个普通的价值就行了。所以，当我在Java中提到新的异常对象时，所以，当我
say something new, something exception class is just an ordinary value. At that
说点新的，例外的类只是一个普通值。在那件事上
point, it just behaves like any other object. But then, there is a distinction
点，它的行为就像任何其他对象一样。但话说回来，这是有区别的
when the object is thrown. So, when the exception is actually thrown, it becomes a
当对象被抛出时。因此，当异常实际引发时，它将成为
special kind of value and it gets treated differently, alright. So, we're going to
一种特殊的价值，它会得到不同的对待，好吧。所以，我们要去
distinguish between an ordinary object V, okay. And objects that have been thrown,
区分一个普通的物体V，好的。以及被抛出的物体，
okay, which are then active exceptions. Alright? So, let's take a look at some of
好的，这就是有效的例外。好吗？那么让我们来看看一些
the operational rules for the exception constructs. So, here's one rule for its
异常构造的操作规则。所以，这是它的一条规则
try-catch-block. And what this rule says is that if an expression evaluates to an
尝尝-接住-挡路。此规则说明的是，如果表达式的计算结果为
ordinary value. If it doesn't throw an exception, then the results of the
普通值。如果它没有引发异常，则
try-catch-block is just that value. So, the way the try-catch-block works is you
尝尝-接住-挡路就是这样的价值。所以，挡路的工作方式就是你
evaluate the expression in the try-block. If that terminates normally with a value,
评估Try-挡路中的表达式。如果它以一个值正常终止，
then the results of the whole expression is just that value, alright? Now, the
那么整个表达式的结果就是那个值，对吗？现在，
other possibility is that you'll evaluate a try catch block and when you go to
另一种可能性是，您将评估一次尝试捕捉挡路，当您转到
evaluate the expression of the try-block E1, it will throw an exception. So, it
评估Try-挡路E1的表达式，它将抛出异常。所以，它
could result in a thrown exception. And so, in this case. Okay, that is that,
可能会导致引发异常。所以，在这种情况下。好的，那就是，
excuse me, that is this case where E1 evaluates to one of these special values
打扰一下，在这种情况下，e1的计算结果是这些特定值之一
has been marked as a thrown exception. What do we do in that case? Well, like
已标记为引发的异常。在这种情况下我们该怎么办？嗯，就像
unwrap the exception, we pull out value that is in the thrown exception, alright.
展开异常，我们取出抛出的异常中的值，好的。
We bind it to some local name, alright, that's named in the catch expression and
我们将其绑定到某个本地名称，该名称在catch表达式中命名
then we evaluate the cleanup code. So, with the ex ception value available, we
然后我们评估清理代码。因此，有了可用的Exception值，我们
evaluate E2 and whatever the result is of E2, that is the result of the
评估E2以及E2的结果是什么，这是
try-catch-block. How does throw work? It's very simple. So, throw just takes an
尝尝-接住-挡路。投掷是怎么做的？这很简单。所以，投掷只需要一次
expression, it evaluates that expression against some value V. And then, it marks
表达式，它根据某个值V对该表达式求值，然后标记
that value as a thrown exception, as a thrown exception so it wraps the value in
将该值作为抛出的异常，作为抛出的异常，因此它将该值包装在
this T thing and that indicate that this exception now has been thrown. Now, the
这个T和那个表示这个异常现在已经被抛出了。现在，
only other thing we need to talk about is how the rest of the language, all the
我们唯一需要谈的就是睡觉的语言，所有的
other constructs in the language deal with these thrown exceptions. And that's very
该语言中的其他构造处理这些抛出的异常。这是非常重要的
simple. We want those thrown exceptions to simply propagate out of any other kind of
很简单。我们希望这些抛出的异常只是从任何其他类型的
expression. So, for example, we'll just do one example here because the idea is the
表达式。举个例子，我们在这里只做一个例子，因为我们的想法是
same for every other language construct. Let's say, that we're evaluating E1 + E2,
对于所有其他语言构造都是如此。比方说，我们评估的是E1+E2，
alright. So, the first thing we have to do of course is to evaluate E1 and if that
好的。所以，我们要做的第一件事当然是评估E1，如果
happens the thrown exception. So, if something goes wrong in the evaluation of
发生引发的异常。因此，如果在评估过程中出现问题
E1 and E1 evaluates to the thrown in exception, well then we stop the
e1和e1的计算结果为抛出的异常，那么我们停止
evaluation of the plus right there. We don't even evaluate E2, notice that E2 is
对那里的加号进行评估。我们甚至不评估E2，请注意E2是
not mentioned here above the line of one of the things to be evaluated so that E1
此处未提及要评估的其中一件事，因此E1
terminates normally with an exception, then the results of the entire addition is
正常终止，但出现异常，则整个加法的结果为
that exception. And similarly, for all the other constructs if, if there's, one of
这是个例外。类似地，对于所有其他构造，如果有一个
their sub-expressions results in an exception. In fact, if the, if, as soon as
它们的子表达式会导致异常。事实上，如果如果，如果，尽快
one of their sub-expressions results in an exception, they stop evaluating and
它们的一个子表达式导致异常，则它们停止计算并
propagate that exception up. The only thing that will stop the exception from
向上传播该异常。唯一可以阻止异常发生的事情是
propagating all the way out to become the result of the whole program is if it is
一直传播成为整个项目的结果是如果它是
caught in a try-catch-block. There are many ways to implement exceptions and here
陷入了一场试抓挡路的游戏。实现异常的方法有很多种，这里
is one simple way to do it. So, we encounter a try expression, we will mark
是做这件事的一种简单方法。因此，我们遇到一个try表达式，我们将标记
the current location in the stack. So, we will mark the position in the stack where
堆栈中的当前位置。因此，我们将在堆栈中标记以下位置
we encountered the try. So, for example, here, say, is our s tack. Let's say that,
我们遇到了一次尝试。举个例子，这里是我们的大头针。这么说吧，
you know, the stack is going this way. We encounter a try expression here so we put
你知道，这堆东西往这边走了。我们在这里遇到了一个try表达式，所以我们把
some kind of marker in the stack to indicate that there's a try that was
堆栈中的某种标记表示有一次尝试
encountered there. And then you go on, you know, evaluating things inside of the try
在那里遇到的。然后你继续，你知道，在试验中进行评估
which might add more stuff to the stack. Now, when we throw an exception, if down
这可能会将更多的内容添加到堆栈中。现在，当我们抛出异常时，如果向下
here, all of a sudden a throw occurs and we're at this point in the execution,
在这里，突然发生了一次投掷，我们在执行死刑的这一点上，
what's going to happen is we're going to unwind the stacks. We're going to knock
接下来会发生的是，我们要把堆栈拆开。我们要去敲门
everything off the stack. We're going to pop all of this stuff of the stack, so
堆叠中的所有东西。我们要把堆栈中的所有东西都放出来，所以
it's all gone, back to the first try. And then we'll execute the corresponding
一切都过去了，回到第一次尝试。然后我们将执行相应的
catch. So, here we marked, you know, the place and the code where there was a try
接住。所以，我们在这里标出了，你知道，试过的地方和代码
and we can use that to find the expression the piece of the code that has the
我们可以使用它来查找表达式，即包含
corresponding catch-block and we'll unwind the stack to that point and then begin
相应的Catch-挡路，我们将展开堆栈到该点，然后开始
evaluation of the catch. So at this particular design it has the disadvantage
对渔获物的评估。所以在这个特殊的设计中，它有一个缺点
that try actually cost something. So, even if you don't throw an, even if you don't
这种尝试实际上是要付出一些代价的。所以，即使你没有抛出，即使你没有
throw an exception, you still pay something to execute a try-catch-block.
抛出一个异常，您仍然需要支付一些费用来执行一个Try-Catch-挡路。
You have to at least mark the stack and, and remember to unmark it of course, when
您至少必须标记堆栈，并且，当然，记住在下列情况下取消标记它
you pop things off the stack when you leave the try-block. So, more complex
当你离开挡路试吃的时候，你会把东西从堆里弹出来。所以，更复杂的是
techniques tries to reduce the cost of try and throw and also trade off between them.
技术试图降低尝试和投掷的成本，并在它们之间进行权衡。
And generally the thing you want to do is because exceptions are probably relatively
一般来说，你想做的事情是因为例外可能相对
rare in, in most programs is to make the cost of try as low as possible, possibly
在，在大多数程序中很少见的是尽可能地降低尝试的成本
at the expense of making throws slightly more expensive. Now, here's a little
代价是让投掷稍微贵一点。现在，这里有一点
trivia question about Java. So, what happens to an uncaught exception as thrown
关于Java的琐碎问题。那么，抛出未捕获的异常会发生什么呢
during object finalization? So, if you don't know what object finalization is,
在对象定版期间？所以，如果你不知道什么是对象终结，
well, when an object is collected, when an object is garbage collected, it is
嗯，当一个对象被收集时，当一个对象被垃圾收集时，它是
possible to run a method on that object to clean it up before the garbage collector
可以在垃圾回收器之前对该对象运行方法以将其清除
actually deallocates it and this is called the finali zation method. So, objects have
实际上解除了它的分配，这被称为终结化方法。所以，物体有
finalization methods in, in Java and those methods are essentially invoked by the
中的终结方法以及Java中的这些方法实质上是由
garbage collector. Some garbage collector discovers that some objects, this garbage
垃圾收集器。一些垃圾回收器发现某些对象、此垃圾
is going to be clean it up, it will first invoke the finalization method. And why
要清理它，它将首先调用finalization方法。为什么？
would you wanted to do this unless, say, we have an object and it might have, say,
你会想这样做吗，除非，比如说，我们有一个物体，它可能有，比如说，
a file handle. It might have a pointer to an open file or something like that. And
文件句柄。它可能有一个指向打开的文件或类似文件的指针。和
now, when this object becomes unreachable, it will be collected by the garbage
现在，当此对象变得不可访问时，它将由垃圾回收
collector. But if you don't close the file, well, that's gonna cause problems.
收藏家。但如果你不关闭文件那就会有问题。
Having lots of open files that are hanging around without the program using them it
有许多打开的文件在没有程序使用的情况下挂起
can cause problems later on, especially if you run out of file handles. Usually,
可能会在以后导致问题，特别是在用完文件句柄的情况下。通常，
there's a fixed number of file handles available from the operating system. So,
操作系统提供固定数量的文件句柄。所以,
the right thing to do is when this is garbage collected is to first close the
正确的做法是在垃圾回收时首先关闭
file and essentially get rid of this pointer, okay, and then, deallocate the
文件，并从本质上消除此指针，好的，然后释放
object, and that it was object finalization is for. So, again, you can
对象，并且它是用于对象终结的。所以，再一次，你可以
define the method in Java that will be run by the garbage collector to kinda clean up
在Java中定义将由垃圾收集器运行以进行某种清理的方法
any resources the object has before it's actually deallocated. And now the question
对象在实际释放之前拥有的所有资源。现在的问题是
is, if that finalization method raises an exception, who catches it? Because it was
是，如果该finalization方法引发异常，谁会捕获它？因为它是
invoked by the garbage collector, it's unpredictable when it's going to be
由垃圾收集器调用，则无法预测它将在何时
invoked and it's not clear where that exception should be handled. And the
调用，并且不清楚应该在哪里处理该异常。以及
answer to the question is no one handles that method or nothing handles that
问题的答案是没有人处理该方法，或者没有任何东西处理该方法
method. The exception is simply dropped. And so, any exceptions that happen during
方法。该例外被简单地丢弃。因此，在此期间发生的任何异常
object finalization that are not handled within the finalization method itself are
未在终结化方法本身内处理的对象终结化是
simply thrown away. One of the nice innovations in Java is that exceptions are
干脆扔掉。Java中的一个很好的创新是异常是
actually part of the method interface and they are checked by the compiler. So, in,
实际上是方法接口的一部分，它们由编译器检查。那么，在，
in the example that I gave at the beginning of this lecture, we had a method
在本课开始时我给出的例子中，我们有一个方法
X that could raise an exception, my exception, and notice that the declaration
这可能会引发异常，我的异常，请注意，声明
of X actually declares that X can throw that exception. So, it's part of the
实际上声明了X可以抛出该异常。所以，这是
interfaced X, part of the checked interfaced X that it can raise a
接口X，这是选中的接口X的一部分，它可以引发
particular exception. And why would you want to check this at compile time? Well,
特别例外。为什么要在编译时检查这一点？井,
the observation that was made, actually in the original Java project was that there
实际上，在最初的Java项目中观察到的是
were many exceptions that could be raised by Java programs and people easily lost
是否有许多Java程序可能引发的异常，人们很容易丢失
rack of what possible exceptions could be raised, they didn't know what exceptions
他们不知道可能会引发什么异常，也不知道有哪些异常
they had to handle. And in fact, when they added this to the language the compiler
他们必须要处理。事实上，当他们把这个添加到语言中时，编译器
would actually enforce now that a method declared every exception it could raise.
现在，方法声明了它可以引发的所有异常，这一点实际上是强制执行的。
They discovered lots of places in the, in the compiler where there were exceptions
他们在编译器中发现了很多有异常的地方
being raised but not properly handled. So, this led to better air handling in, in the
被养大但没有得到妥善处理的。所以，这导致了更好的空气处理，在
Java compiler itself, and, and I think people generally agree that this is een a
Java编译器本身，我想人们普遍同意这甚至是一种
good idea because it helps programmers to write more robust code because they can
好主意，因为它可以帮助程序员编写更健壮的代码，因为他们可以
see exactly which exceptions they have to handle. Now, there are some exceptions to
确切地查看他们必须处理哪些异常。现在，有一些例外
this rule. In particular there's, there's some kinds of runtime errors that don't
这条规则。尤其是，有一些类型的运行时错误不会
have to be part of the method signature simply because it's very hard to check
必须是方法签名的一部分，因为很难检查
statistically that the method would never raise them. So, things like dereferencing
从统计学上讲，这种方法永远不会提高它们。所以，像取消引用这样的事情
null or interprocedural overflow don't have to be handled and declared in the
NULL或过程间溢出不必在
interface. But for the most part any exception that a, a method can raise has
接口。但是在大多数情况下，一个方法可以引发的任何异常都有
to be declared as part of its interface in Java. And then there are other
在Java中声明为其接口的一部分。然后还有其他的
mundane-type rules about the particular design for exceptions in Java. So, for
关于Java中异常的特定设计的普通类型规则。所以，对于
example, throw has to be applied to an object of type exception, it can't be
例如，抛出必须应用于类型为Exception的对象，而不能
applied to an object of an arbitrary type. But overall exceptions are rather nicely
应用于任意类型的对象。但总体而言，例外情况相当不错
done in Java and that this particular idea of, of declaring the types of exceptions
这是用Java完成的，这个声明异常类型的特定想法
that a method can raise was a new idea in Java.
方法可以引发的问题在Java中是一个新概念。